Finding Aid for the A. Brown Co. Records LSC.0687
UCLA Library Special Collections
A. Brown Co. records
1880-1935
UCLA Library Special Collections
Brown, Andrew
LSC.0687
9.0 Linear Feet (16 document boxes and 1 oversize carton)
Andrew Brown (1829-1909) was born in Ireland. In 1852, he sailed around Cape Horn to San Francisco. He later went into the mercantile business, purchased thousands of acres of land, built a flour mill and a lumber mill and became engaged extensively in farming as well as raising cattle and horses. The collection consists of correspondence, business papers, receipts, bills, and other papers connected with Andrew Brown's store in Kernville, California, his jobs as postmaster and agent for the Wells Fargo and Company's Express, and his other business interests.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mr. P. Sumner Brown and Mrs. Elizabeth B. Pallette, August 1935.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942302863606533
Biography
Andrew Brown was one of the pioneers of Kernville. He was born in Ireland on September 15, 1829; came to Philadelphia as a young man and in 1852 sailed around Cape Horn to San Francisco; after a try at mining and farming, he went to Kernville and operated the quartz mill of Joseph W. Sumner, whose daughter he married in 1873; later went into the mercantile business, owning a very successful general store at Kernville and one at Weldon; was owner of thousands of acres of land, and became engaged extensively in farming and raising cattle and horses; built a flour mill and a lumber mill; was known throughout Kern County as a prominent and active citizen; retired in 1904 and moved to Los Angeles; he died on October 12, 1909.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of correspondence, business papers, receipts, bills, and other papers connected with Andrew Brown's store in Kernville, California, his jobs as postmaster and agent for the Wells Fargo and Company's Express, and his other business interests.
Pioneers -- California -- Kern County -- Archives.; Brown, Andrew--Archives.; A. Brown Co.--Archives
- Correspondence, 1900-1935
  - Correspondence: A-C, 1918-1932 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: D, 1918-1932 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: E, 1918-1932 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: F, 1918-1932 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: G, 1918-1932 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: H, 1918-1932 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: I-J, 1918-1932 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: K, 1918-1932 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: L, 1918-1932 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: M, 1918-1932 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: N-O, 1918-1932 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: P-Q, 1918-1932 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: R, 1918-1932 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1930-1933 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1930-1931 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1919-1926 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1920-1930 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1920-1924 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1930s (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: Security Trust Co., 1910s-1920s (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Boston and Kern River, 1910 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1910 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Baker, Hamilton, and Pacific Co., 1910s (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Southern California Edison Co., 1919-1922 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Standard Oil Co., 1919-1922 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: D.A. Syme, 1918-1919 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Dr. Smith, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Thomas Scott, 1917-1918 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence and catalogs, 1910s (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: National Protective Agency, 1910s-20s (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: International Harvester Co., 1918-1921 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1900-1920 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1914-1920 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1910-1925 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1914-1922 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1904-1925 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: P. Sumner Brown, 1907-1922 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: A, 1920s (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: B, 1910s (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: M, 1910s-1920s (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: S, 1910-1929 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: U, 1910s-1920s (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: W, 1910s-1920s (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: American Protective League, 1918-1922 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Cattlemen's Protective League, 1918-1926 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Taylor, Chas C., 1918-1920 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Weber Showcase and Fixture Co., 1918 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: John C. Moore Corporation, 1917-1920 (Box 15, Folder 13)
- Records, 1890-1935
  - Booklets: Vienna Technische Museum fur Industrie and Gewerbe (German), 1930s (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Financial records: Standard Oil Co., 1922-1924 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Financial records: Standard Oil Co., 1921-1923 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Financial records, 1923-1924 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Financial records, 1922-1923 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Ledger, 1935-1936 (Box 3)
  - Receipt books, 1921-1922 (Box 3)
  - Directories, 1926, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Catalog: Union Hardware and Metal Co., undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Postmaster's Postal Account Books, 1915-1921 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Financial records, 1936-1937 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Financial records, 1925 (Box 5)
  - Telegraph records and financial records, 1920 (Box 6)
  - Service Station Order Book, 1922 (Box 7)
  - Order Book, 1933 (Box 7)
  - Pay Roll book, 1923-1935 (Box 7)
  - Weldon Store Order Book, 1915-1917 (Box 7)
  - Ledger book, 1926 (Box 7)
  - Order Book ledgers: "China Book", 1890s-1920s (Box 8)
  - Leather ledger, circa 1920s (Box 8)
  - Inventory ledgers, 1930s (Box 8)
  - Receipt book, 1921 (Box 8)
  - Financial records, 1920s (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
  - Financial records, 1933 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Financial records, 1930s (Box 9, Folder 4-5)
  - Meteorological records, 1890s-1930s (Box 10)
  - Ledger books, circa early 1900s (Box 11)
  - Ledger books, circa early 1900s (Box 12)
  - Financial records, 1940-1941 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Financial records, 1930s (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Financial records, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Financial records, 1935-1937 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Liberty Bond Payments, 1920-1923 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Receipts, 1935-1936 (Box 15, Folder 14-15)
  - Financial Records: Cash Book, District Post Offices, 1924 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Merchandise Inventory, Weldon Store, 1920-1922 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Ledger books, 1927-1934 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Catalogs, circa 1930s (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Meteorological records, 1900-1931 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous, 1920s-1930s (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous, 1900-1910 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Deed and stock certificates, circa 1900 (Box 17)
  - Financial records, circa 1900 (Box 17)
  - Transfer Ledger oversize book, circa 1900 (Box 17)